#### **ONYINYE CATHERINE CHUKWUMA**

Ajah, Lagos | +234(0)8160558186 | onyinyechukwuma14@gmail.com | github.com/onyiii

#### **PERSONAL PROFILE**

Experienced and Motivated Customer Service Professional with expertise in operations strategies, expanding new business, and providing unparalleled customer support. Gained comprehensive experience and knowledge in customer relationship management, regulatory compliance, and general operational support.

Pivoting into Technology and Software development through self-directed training on responsive web design and JavaScript data structures and algorithms to develop skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React and learning multiple systems and efficient development techniques.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS & TECHNOLOGIES**

✓ HTML5 ✓ CSS ✓ Bootstrap ✓ Javascript ✓ React ✓ Python ✓ Microsoft Dynamic CRM ✓ Data Analysis ✓ Git ✓Github ✓Material UI ✓ Microsoft Office: Excel and PowerPoint ✓ Strategic Operations Planning ✓Azure Devops ✓Figma ✓Agile

### **SOFT SKILLS**

- √ Customer Relationship Management and People Management ✓ Problem-solving ✓ Teamwork
- ✓ Effective Communication and Presentation ✓ Critical thinking ✓ Resourcefulness ✓ Strategic Operations Planning ✓ Business Development/Growth

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Altschool Africa April 2022 – Date

#### √ Frontend Developer

- Strategically combining work with my classes and online videos
- Finishing my assignments and tasks within due date
- Solved some problems on Leetcode so as to boost my data structure and algorithm skills
- Taking up courses on Youtube and Udemy to complement my classes
- Hosted some of my works on Netlify (github.com/onyiii)

# GTBank Plc, Oniru Lekki Lagos

Sept 2022 - Date

#### √ Solution Architect

- I ensure that all the requirements of the stakeholders as regards software product development are taken into account
- Understanding all the constraints of the products, compare them, and then make a number of technological and managerial decisions to reconcile these restrictions with project goals
- Analyzing and documenting requirements
- Creating a solution prototype
- Setting collaboration Network
- Updating the Azure board and monitoring the movement of tasks on the board.

- Organizing sprint planning, sprint review and retrospective
- Making sure that each task is analyzed before taking it up in a sprint so as to ensure quality and speedy delivery
- Checking the tasks and helping to resolve any problem the developers might encounter
- Managing the backlogs and ensuring right prioritization of tasks
- Charged with ensuring that the card and Chequebook templates are updated and acknowledging

## GTBank Plc, Oniru Lekki Lagos

Feb 2021 - Date

## √ Customer Information Service (Branch Lead)

- Cross-selling of Gtbank products across the value chain of corporate customers.
- Relationship management and resolution of client queries and challenges
- Play instrumental role checking mails received and responding accordingly.
- Mastermind and lead efforts to check CRM and treat requests for CIS; print out dispense error complaints and ensure complaints are resolved before resolution time expires.
- Handled Branch Audit Operations.
- Outperform expectations processing customer requests timely, as well as account officer mails/requests.
- Execute strategies and initiatives to print BO call over reports (standing instruction call over, Chequebook profile report, E-one call-over report, and Card link report) and review for errors.
- Charged with ensuring that the card and Chequebook templates are updated and acknowledging Card and Chequebook received on E-tracker.
- Enhanced quality outcomes ensuring all CIS transactions are approved and filed.

## Administrative Assistant in Divine Medical Centre Ikoyi (2018 – 2020)

- I make decisions and take actions on behalf of the hospital in ensuring that clients' interests are protected at all times
- I run and manage the financial activities of the company like preparing the bills for all the HMOs, the drug and medical equipment suppliers and confirming payments too.
- I also act as the intermediary between the hospital and these HMOs and suppliers
- I ensure that all the appliances in the hospitals are running and makes contact with the vendors for any needed resolution.
- I am responsible for all clerical duties such as filing, photocopying, and organising documents for future reference.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Altschool Africa**

Frontend development

April 2022(ongoing)

Tech Studio

Oct 2021 – February 2022

Fullstack Development Career Path

## University of Nigeria, Nigeria

B.Sc. Microbiology.

## Dec 2010 - Jan 2015

### **AWARDS AND CERTIFICATIONS**

## **LinkedIn Learning**

√Project Management ✓Learning Python ✓Excel Statistics Essential Training ✓Data Analysis and Visualization.

## **Udemy Learning**

√Web design for Web developers √CyberSecurity Training for New Hires √ Best QA Manual Software testing

## GTBank Plc, Mobolaji Bank Anthony, Ikeja, Lagos

**January 2020 – April 2020** 

Entry Level Training Program - Courses taken include:

✓ Basic Finance ✓ Proficient in Microsoft Office ✓ Basic Accounting ✓ International trade finance ✓ Emotional Intelligence ✓ Basic treasury ✓ Financial statement analysis

✓ Enterprise Risk Management ✓ Macro and Micro Economics